Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 65.
We are asked to write a function to rotate the injured list counterclockwise.
So, for example, consider a linked list that contains data a b.
This is in kidneys and kidneys.
OK, and we have solved this exercise in singly linked list.
So in the kidneys, we should take care about that extra pointer, which is the previous OK, and we
should think about the linkage.
So this points, we have concentrate on them over the next in the previous exercises.
So pay attention, guys.
This is the array.
This is sorted there.
Linked list before rotation.
Now we need to rotate this array by four, K four and equal to three.
So I need to rotate these these elements by like an equal by and equal to two.
OK.
So but here there is a trick.
It is counterclockwise.
OK, you got a guys counter-clockwise.
So what does this mean?
I need not to put from this element, but this element at last I put it in the first.
So this is clockwise.
OK?
Putting elements from the end to that to the beginning.
This is clockwise.
I need to remove the elements from the first and put it on the left.
So this is counter-clockwise.
So this is that counterclockwise?
OK.
You get guys.
So if I need to get.
Rotate and rotate this link, at least by two by and equal to do an equal to do so, I need to remove
two elements from the first and put it at the end.
So I will remove one.
Put it here and then I will remove B and put it here.
So the final?
The result would be if A and B have been removed, C would be the first one.
Okay.
Now.
The second one is following the.
You see, guys, this is their rotation.
He here now.
What is the first element that I have retained rotated?
It is a.
So I will link it with a.
Now, what is the next phase of this will be?
It is the note be.
OK, guys.
This is B so b now refers to now.
And C refers to the previous note.
OK.
This is the trick behind rotation.
So how to do that in coding, how to do that in Java and in terms of coding, we pay attention for that
links.
OK.
This is what we are going to make.
But before we continue, I should mention that this this rotation will cost us time, complexity of
of.
And you can see the complexity of all the exercises that we have made and the source code in the up
and the resource folder on our Udemy course.
So you can get them all by doing like this.
We scroll down till like if I need to get the complexity of this, I click on it and I see that that
is off and we have solved this in our exit exercise number 64 in the previous slides.
So let's make a method called.
Rotate and this rotate method, which took a perimeter, and so how many and will define that?
How many and nodes or how many rotation you you should make for this for this link at least.
So public
static void rotate.
How many times or how many degrees I should make it and will define it?
OK.
Smaller, yeah.
OK, now if I would check if the user enters and as a as an equal to zero, I should not make anything,
so I'm not rotating anything.
If an equal equal to zero, then return.
Let us understand that they're not care and equal to have that we should refer in, you know, that
indicates the position of the head.
OK.
So in order to do that, I will create if a node called node current equal to had.
What is head head will indicate for us here?
So I should not make static in order to get.
And get the reference and get the.
Instance from above.
OK, let me first step.
Make it making or indicating the indicating the first part of the beginning.
No current will either point to end or now after this loop, current will point to the Node B in the
order point, like B or C in the above example.
So it will return B or point to be equal to one.
Now we are creating a wild blue.
While.
Count.
Less than an and and current does not equal to none.
Then go and put the current equal to current dot next.
OK.
Count increased count by one.
This is the count, and this is how we indicate the first.
And the structure of that link, at least if current equal, equal to null then and is greater than
or equal to the count of nodes and link at least.
So that's a check for check for.
And if government equal equal to none, then editor OK, now the third step is Carolyn now points to
the end note.
Current
points to and note, OK, this is good now stored it in a valuable starting.
Starting current in that, what is this variable of type note called and no equal to?
Correct.
OK.
We have found the best.
No, it's best, no.
And we need to start our rotation.
Kernot will point to the last note after this loop, so I will make a loop pointing, pointing to last
note.
Okay, so this loop current will point to Note E in in the above example.
So it is the last known line current and the next does not equal to null.
Then current will be equal to current dog.
Next, we have stored there beginning and if we are going to rotate by two, so current now equal to
two ends note we have stored it and we have found that second note or byte by K. equal to or an equal
to and current now move to the last known why?
Because change.
Then changing the next of the last note the previous had because we are updating here in step number
five, updating the links.
The linkage.
Okay, so next of E!
Is now change to Node A.
This is how we have how to make it next equal to had because HAB is now next to the last one because
we have removed a from the beginning and put it in the and after eight now.
Number six, step number six, I know that it may be confused sometimes, but if you keep practicing
and you understand what I am doing step by step, it would be very easy.
Now change the previous of head no to curtain previous of a is now changed to no.
Keep updating the linkage.
This has occurred because the next and the previous we should take care about it.
So had the previous equal to occurred, OK, I have guessed it now.
Change the head to end plus one at the f node and head is now changed.
Do not see changing the other set.
Six Changing the other pointers had equal to any snow dot next and had thought the previous.
That's true equal to none.
OK.
Change of venue had No.
Two now because of previous head note in a linked list and has none.
OK.
It's very simple.
Now the last step is changing the next of no to none change the next of last note to a.
And snowed dot next equal to none.
OK, now.
Let's see our example here.
I have the list is.
99, two and four.
I need to rotate it by one.
So 99 should be here at the end and two becomes the first.
This is their algorithm behind this example.
So let's call the AL and don't rotate by one system that or we call the and dark breadth the last list.
The other hand, had system that allowed the sprint.
After rotation.
That's around, Nancy.
And here we go, guys.
After rotation, we are printing in forward way.
It was nine nine in nineteen, ninety nine, two and four.
It becomes ninety nine goes through here to the end, so do becomes the first, four becomes the second
and 99 becomes the last.
And this is the trick behind this.
This third rotation method and its complexity, it's of course, all of and because we are going through
all of these notes of the double link, at least in this way, we have learned about rotation and rotating
the double link at list elements by and position.